<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lifeblog</title>
    <description>A simple, beautiful theme for Jekyll that emphasizes content rather than aesthetic fluff.</description>
    <link>http://iamit.in/lifeblog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://iamit.in/lifeblog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The Joy Of Being Good</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What it takes to become bad? Simply nothing, but it takes a lot of character and goodness to become good. The Joy of being good is equally larger as the pain of being bad, but still most of us trudge the second path. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is due to the myopia of short term gain, the second path appears to be the bed of roses to many of us. That’s off course an illusion by which we are allured and get easily trapped into the bait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the second path promises short term pleasures and quick fixes, but it can never guarantee you the lifetime pleasure. By choosing the second path we may be overwhelmed by its initial offerings but we have to pay the price for it in future. Hence the second path which appears to be the easier one is actually the tougher one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely the first path may not promise for the short term pleasures but guarantees you sure shot high on self esteem, confidence and also the Peace of the soul. Then why not choose the first path than to become the slave of our own deeds in the second path? Change is always undesirable and human being particularly tends to resist change. Though getting on to the first path is not too difficult, but it’s a matter of will and determination to get on the right track. It’s rightly said in bhagwad gita:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Chanchala hi mana, abhyase hi vasham”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means mind is easily enchanted by the lure of the negative, but can be controlled by Practice. One has to change the default programming of his mind to explore the Joy of being Good. Tough, but not the toughest! And hence the Joy is extremely larger!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/08/08/The%20Joy%20Of%20Being%20Good/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/08/08/The%20Joy%20Of%20Being%20Good/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Law Of KARMA &amp;#58; A Bank Transaction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is “Karma”? There are infinite answers to this question by infinite philosophies but what the Karma actually is? Karma is the ultimate law of nature whose mechanism is very much similar to that of bank transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we are born an account on our name is automatically opened in the ‘bank of karma’. At that time we have nil balance i.e. our destiny is not defined. As we grow older our deeds and actions pay to our account and makes our destiny. Our good deeds are debited, and as a bank account when we deposit something we get interest along with the deposited amount, we get more than what we give by doing good deeds. The converse is true as well, we have  to pay more than what we take by doing bad deeds same as in bank’s mechanism we have to pay abundant interest to the bank for the loan we take, hence bad deeds are credited as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mechanism mentioned above truly describes the Law of Karma if the concept of rebirth is not taken into account. The question which is of prime importance when the concept of rebirth is considered is that &lt;em&gt;why some are born more blessed than others?&lt;/em&gt; One is born in a palace and other in a slum. This may be answered by considering the actions of last birth, which are also counted while landing on earth i.e. the sum total of debit and credit of the account of last birth. It means we may not get the fresh account every birth, one single account is issued to the soul, no matter the number of births one may take his account is always active!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Theories on Karma and rebirth are mere postulates, nothing can said with due sureity. It’s our experiences which tells about the validity of a particular theory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/07/12/Law%20Of%20%E2%80%9CKARMA%E2%80%9D:%20A%20Bank%20Transaction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/07/12/Law%20Of%20%E2%80%9CKARMA%E2%80%9D:%20A%20Bank%20Transaction/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Art Of Living</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s the ultimate art of living? The question which has haunted us since we were enlightened enough about the phenomenon of life!  Although, yet most of us are striving for the excellent living. We must have come across infinite answers to this question by infinite philosophies.  Obviously Then, arises the question which one is perfect and implementable? Even this article is teaching one!!. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple don’t follow any. We all are gifted with the most powerful inbuilt instrument i.e. our brain. The only thing we need to know is how to use it elegantly. This is for sure that before we came to this question we must have live or “experienced” some portion of our life. That Experience is the tool to use the machine named brain. That’s all and we would get the answer to all our questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One doesn’t need to doomed into million sources to learn the art of living neither one need mentor to learn this art, rather the answer is within our experiences. Our experiences teach us the ultimate art of living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than Seven thousand sculptures flocked together to built the marvelous akshardham temple, but do you know the number of sculpture needed to mould ourselves?
Just &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; and that’s we ourselves! The key to being happy is to change our aspired tendency to resist the necessary change needed to be bought in our life to learn the ultimate art of living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/07/10/The%20Art%20Of%20Living/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/07/10/The%20Art%20Of%20Living/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple Is Extraordinary</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The difference between being great and being successful&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many a times while reading the biography of some great men we may wonder why we aren’t like them or what differentiates them from others and what should may be done to become like them. We may subconsciously arrive at the conclusion that, they were born with some extraordinary skills which are horned later in there life and eventually they are extraordinary. Though this is off course not true since once greatness is not a matter of chance or luck, it’s a matter of attitude which is common in all great men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplicity though sounds to be very simple but makes the difference between ordinary and extraordinary as we can aspire to touch the sky only when we are down to earth. Although, being simple alone doesn’t certify for one’s greatness but measure’s it to a great extent. Being simple doesn’t only mean wearing simple clothes or putting simple boots but keeping your attitude simple, and your character to be an open book. If we talk of Mahatma Gandhi the ‘great’ he also had a simple philosophy of “Simple living and high thinking”, not only mahatma Gandhi, all great men had these feature common hence there is no doubt that greatness resides in simplicity. So to become great be simple, and to being simple just forget about those scars and pimples on your face, forget thinking about what people will say about you, forget about all mundane things, and hence you are simple! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is indeed ridiculous to know that, nowadays, many stars and not so famous personalities are getting involved in cheap and mundane activities, just to gain some name and fame, but being renowned all over the globe or over the nation doesn’t mean to be great; One is great by his activity not by his publicity. To be great, it’s not necessary to be called as “great” by others; instead we must listen “great” from our soul, to be truly great.&lt;br&gt;
Be Simple and yes, you are extraordinary! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 16:51:29 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/06/08/Simple%20Is%20Extraordinary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/06/08/Simple%20Is%20Extraordinary/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raj Kapoor&amp;#58;  The Legend</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know about the famous Actor, Director, Producer, and the ultimate showman of Indian cinema i.e. &lt;strong&gt;Raj Kapoor&lt;/strong&gt; The man with an extraordinary but a simple philosophy. His films were not only made to extract profit but to teach humanity, brotherhood and of course the ideal art of living. The music in his films had a different rhythm whose lyrics had a soulful meaning which carried the aroma of mankind. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast to today’s movies and music they are intentionally made to earn huge profit and fame by destroying moral and ethical values and are solely inspired from the west. Many a times I wonder why to look at west, when the sun rises from east! India, the country of its rich culture and heritage is losing its identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raj Kapoor was not only renowned in India, but also in other parts of the globe, especially Russia. His movie “&lt;strong&gt;Mera naam Joker&lt;/strong&gt;” had a great success in Russia though it didn’t run initially in India, probably it was too ahead of it’s times. In this movie Raj played the role of a joker &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued…..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/05/04/Raj%20Kapoor%20The%20Legend/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamit.in/lifeblog/2011/05/04/Raj%20Kapoor%20The%20Legend/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
